<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Data for Democracy Lab</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Data for Democracy Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Michele Claibourn</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debate Watch!</title>
      <link>/2017/09/14/2017-09-14-debate-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/14/2017-09-14-debate-watch/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Debates Campaigns debates are an interesting platform – one of the only opportunities for the candidates to appear together, in a symmetric sort of setting for the viewers (and the candidates). And one of the few moments when aspiring leaders can speak at length to a mass audience about their values, priorities, and policy intentions.
The first general election debate of 2016 broke records for presidential debate viewership, with about 84M viewers; this fell in the second debate with a still re-spectable 67M (against NFL football), and a third place record of 72M for the third debate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/23/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/2014/04/02/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/02/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>